Hello, everyone, and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katrin, and today we've got some kids for you in this dialogue.
我是Katrin，今天我们的对话里有一些孩子。
They're doing something that's very common in America.
他们在做一件在美国很常见的事情。
I'm not so sure if it's common elsewhere, but we'll find that out later.
我不确定在其他地方是否常见，但我们稍后会知道。
So today we're going to ask for money because we are having a fundraiser.
所以今天我们要去筹款，因为我们正在举办一个募捐活动。
So this is a very interesting word.
这是一个很有趣的词。
Why don't we take a look at it in Vocabulary Preview?
我们不如在词汇预览里看看它？
So a fundraiser is a thing.
所以募捐活动是一个东西。
It's an event.
它是一个活动。
It's something that you do at a school or a business to try and collect money for a
这是你在学校或公司做的一件事，目的是为某个
special event or charity.
特殊活动或慈善机构筹集资金。
That's right.
没错。
So money, you can also say is funds, right?
所以钱，你也可以说成资金，对吧？
And that's what you're trying to do.
这就是你想做的事情。
You're trying to collect.
你在尝试收集。
You're trying to gather a lot of money or funds in order for, like you say, some sort
你在尝试聚集很多钱或资金，为了，就像你说的，某种
of objective purpose.
目标或目的。
Right.
对。
So it's not just like we're having a fundraiser to earn more profits this year.
所以这不只是我们今年办个募捐活动来赚更多利润。
It's usually an event that's for some kind of charity or good cause.
它通常是一个为了某种慈善或善举的活动。
So for example, the company is having a fundraiser for Jenny's child because he's sick and they
比如，公司为Jenny的孩子办募捐活动，因为他生病了，他们
can't pay for medical care.
付不起医疗费。
So a fundraiser is for a good cause.
所以募捐活动是为了善举。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So that's what this dialogue is all about today.
这就是今天这个对话的全部内容。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a bit.
我们不如第一次听一下对话，稍后再回来。
Okay, Mark, it's your turn to ring the doorbell.
好的，Mark，轮到你去按门铃了。
I did it last time.
上次是我按的。
I hate going door to door and I hate asking for money.
我讨厌挨家挨户跑，也讨厌要钱。
But we need to raise enough money for the school fundraiser so that our class can win
但我们需要为学校的募捐活动筹够钱，这样我们班才能赢得
the pizza party.
披萨派对。
You do want to have a pizza party, don't you?
你确实想要一个披萨派对，对吧？
Yes, but...
是的，但是……
Just go already.
赶紧去吧。
No one's coming.
没人来开门。
Try again.
再试一次。
Maybe there's no one home.
也许没人在家。
Of course there's someone home.
当然有人在家。
There are two cars in the driveway and I can see lights on in the house.
车道上停着两辆车，而且我能看到房子里亮着灯。
Hello?
你好？
Anybody home?
有人在家吗？
We would like to know if you want to sponsor us in our school fundraiser.
我们想问您是否愿意赞助我们的学校募捐活动。
50% of the profits go towards the new school playground.
50%的利润将用于新的学校操场。
I don't know why anyone would want what's in this catalogue anyway.
我不知道为什么会有人想要这本目录里的东西。
It's just a bunch of tacky Christmas ornaments.
只是一堆俗气的圣诞装饰品。
CDs of old people singing Christmas songs and special crackers and cheeses and boxes
老人唱圣诞歌的CD，还有特别的饼干、奶酪和盒子
of chocolate.
装的巧克力。
You don't like chocolate?
你不喜欢巧克力吗？
Not this kind.
不是这种。
They've got weird names like ganache and praline.
它们有奇怪的名字，比如甘纳许和果仁糖。
Look, I just saw someone walking around inside.
看，我刚才看到有人在里面走动。
These people are being very rude.
这些人太没礼貌了。
Finally, someone's coming.
终于有人来了。
They don't look too happy.
他们看起来不太高兴。
Hi, sir.
你好，先生。
Would you like to sponsor us or make a donation to...
您愿意赞助我们或为……捐款吗？
What grade are you kids in?
你们是几年级的孩子？
Grade 7.
七年级。
Then for goodness sake, don't you see this sign?
那看在上帝的份上，你们没看到这个牌子吗？
Can't you read?
你们不识字吗？
No soliciting.
禁止推销。
Alright, so obviously the kids are selling candy and a lot of different things for their
好了，很明显孩子们在卖糖果和很多不同的东西，为了他们的
new playground.
新操场。
That's the fundraiser, right?
这就是募捐活动，对吧？
So they use a lot of interesting words and phrases there.
所以他们用了很多有趣的词和短语。
Why don't we take a look at a couple of them on Language Takeaway.
我们不如在语言要点里看看其中几个。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, the first word is one that Marco, you've already talked a little bit about today.
嗯，第一个词是Marco你今天已经稍微提到过的。
We talked about fundraiser, to raise.
我们谈到了募捐活动，筹集。
Well, we do have the verb here, to raise enough money.
嗯，我们这里确实有动词，筹够钱。
So raise is a verb that means to collect or gather or to get.
所以筹集是一个动词，意思是收集、聚集或得到。
That's right.
没错。
So you wouldn't really say we are collecting money or we are gathering money.
所以你通常不会说我们在收集钱或我们在聚集钱。
You say we are raising money for the victims of the earthquake in Haiti.
你会说我们正在为海地地震的受害者筹款。
That's right.
没错。
And the reason we don't say we are earning money is because you're not doing any work.
我们不说是赚钱，是因为你没有做任何工作。
Right.
对。
Really, you're not going to the job at 9 o'clock and leaving the job at 5 o'clock.
实际上，你不是早上9点上班、下午5点下班。
You're actually asking people for donations.
你是在向人们请求捐款。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's what you're doing.
所以这就是你在做的事。
You are raising money.
你在筹款。
And now moving on, another way that you can help people maybe through a charity or donation
现在继续，另一种帮助他人的方式，也许是通过慈善机构或捐款，
is also to sponsor.
就是赞助。
To sponsor someone or something.
赞助某人或某物。
Okay, so people can sponsor events or people and companies can also do this as well.
好的，所以人们可以赞助活动或人，公司也可以这样做。
So to sponsor someone is basically to give them money in support of a cause.
所以赞助某人基本上就是给他们钱以支持某个事业。
For example, have you ever done one of those 5K runs or 10K runs?
例如，你参加过那种5公里跑或10公里跑吗？
Did you have to collect sponsors basically to find people who would help pay money for
你是不是需要收集赞助，基本上就是找人愿意为
you to do this run?
你参加这个跑步活动付钱？
Not personally, but I know people who have, who actually get companies interested and
我个人没有，但我认识有人这样做过，他们让公司感兴趣，
maybe that person, for example, is going to run 5K in this race in order to raise money
比如那个人要跑5公里比赛，目的是为某种严重疾病的受害者筹款。
for victims of some serious illness.
然后他们找赞助商，让公司为这个事业捐款。
And so they get sponsors, they get companies to donate money for this cause.
对。
Right.
You could have a person or a company sponsor you, they could be your sponsor by giving
你可以让一个人或公司赞助你，他们可以成为你的赞助商，给你钱，
you money that you can then use for this charity or special cause.
然后你可以用这些钱来做慈善或特殊事业。
That's right.
没错。
So the difference between a fundraiser and to sponsor something or someone is that sponsoring
所以筹款活动和赞助某人或某物的区别在于，赞助
is not always for a charity or for some sort of non-profit cause, right?
并不总是为了慈善或某种非营利事业，对吧？
We have many sponsors for concerts or for sporting events.
我们有很多音乐会的赞助商或体育赛事的赞助商。
That's right.
没错。
So oftentimes when you see athletes, they have their sponsors or their sponsors logos
所以很多时候你看到运动员，他们身上有赞助商或赞助商的标志
written all over their jerseys, the clothes that they wear.
印在他们的球衣上，也就是他们穿的衣服上。
So for example, if you're watching Formula One racing, you see the Ferrari and the bank
例如，如果你看一级方程式赛车，你会看到法拉利和银行
emblems and all these different things.
的标志以及各种不同的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So those are different ways of sponsoring events or people.
所以这些都是赞助活动或人的不同方式。
And now moving on, we have a word that's not really related to money and fundraisers, but
现在继续，我们有一个词，它和钱及筹款活动关系不大，
it's a very interesting word and very common.
但非常有趣且很常见。
When the kids mention that they're selling a bunch of tacky Christmas ornaments.
当孩子们提到他们在卖一堆俗气的圣诞装饰品时。
Tacky.
俗气。
So we're going to hear this a lot and the interesting thing about the word tacky is
所以我们会经常听到这个词，而有趣的是，俗气这个词
that it means something different to everyone.
对每个人来说意义不同。
So what I think is tacky might be just normal for Marco and what Marco thinks is really
所以我觉得俗气的东西，对Marco来说可能很正常，而Marco觉得非常
tacky might be something that I actually like.
俗气的东西，可能是我喜欢的。
And so tacky is basically a bad thing.
所以俗气基本上是个贬义词。
It means something is not good looking or not very fashionable.
它意味着某物不好看或不太时尚。
It's like in bad taste.
就像品味差。
But as you say, taste is something subjective, right?
但正如你所说，品味是主观的，对吧？
So maybe for example, sometimes we say that when girls wear too much makeup, it's very
所以例如，有时我们说女孩化妆太浓，很
tacky, bright red lipstick and blue eyeshadow.
俗气，比如亮红色口红和蓝色眼影。
Exactly.
没错。
So a guy might say, oh, that's so tacky.
所以一个男人可能会说，哦，那太俗气了。
Whereas another person might not think it's tacky at all.
而另一个人可能完全不觉得俗气。
So this happens a lot and we use this word a lot with decorations, for example, for someone's
所以这种情况经常发生，我们经常用这个词来形容装饰品，比如某人的
house, you may describe it as tacky or a restaurant or a bar.
房子，你可以说它俗气，或者餐厅或酒吧。
Right.
对。
So for maybe sometimes those Italian restaurants that have the red and white checkered table
所以比如有时那些意大利餐厅，有红白格子桌布
claws and the pictures of the Italians with the mustaches, I might think that's a little
和留着小胡子的意大利人照片，我可能会觉得有点
bit tacky.
俗气。
But maybe you think it's cute.
但也许你觉得很可爱。
Right.
对。
So something that's tacky.
所以就是俗气的东西。
And as we say, people use it all the time.
正如我们所说，人们经常用这个词。
And it's not necessarily a bad thing.
而且它不一定是坏事。
You can just say, oh, it's a little bit tacky or I think this thing is a little bit tacky.
你可以只说，哦，有点俗气，或者我觉得这个东西有点俗气。
Okay.
好的。
And that's it, right?
就这样，对吧？
Solicit.
招揽。
Okay.
好的。
So a little bit of a language takeaway, towards the end of the dialogue, when the kids were
所以有一点语言要点，在对话快结束时，当孩子们
reading the sign, the sign said, no soliciting.
读牌子时，牌子上写着“禁止招揽”。
And they didn't understand what that means.
他们不明白这是什么意思。
What does it mean when you have a sign that says no soliciting?
当有一个牌子写着“禁止招揽”时，它是什么意思？
Okay.
好的。
So to solicit is to try to sell something or to offer a service.
所以招揽就是试图卖东西或提供服务。
So basically the sign means, please don't come to my house and sell me stuff.
所以基本上这个牌子意味着，请不要来我家卖东西给我。
For example, we have door to door insurance salesmen or makeup salespeople.
例如，我们有上门推销的保险销售员或化妆品销售员。
And these people go to your door and they try to sell you their product.
这些人来到你家门口，试图卖给你他们的产品。
And no soliciting means, don't come to my house.
而“禁止招揽”意味着，不要来我家。
I'm not going to answer the door if you're trying to sell something.
如果你试图卖东西，我不会开门。
So to solicit is to try and sell something.
所以招揽就是试图卖东西。
Okay.
好的。
But usually in person, trying to make a sale uninvited, right?
但通常是亲自上门，未经邀请就试图销售，对吧？
Because if you're a businessman and you have a meeting, a sales meeting, you're not really
因为如果你是个商人，有一个会议，一个销售会议，你并不是真的
soliciting with that other person.
在招揽那个人。
No, this is basically trying to sell something to a stranger.
不，这基本上就是在向陌生人推销东西。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So a lot of interesting words there.
所以那里有很多有趣的词汇。
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back shortly with Fluency Builder.
让我们再听一遍对话，稍后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
Okay, Mark, it's your turn to ring the doorbell.
好的，马克，轮到你去按门铃了。
I did it last time.
上次是我按的。
I hate going door to door and I hate asking for money.
我讨厌挨家挨户地跑，也讨厌要钱。
But we need to raise enough money for the school fundraiser so that our class can win
但我们需要为学校的筹款活动筹集足够的钱，这样我们班才能赢得
the pizza party.
披萨派对。
You do want to have a pizza party, don't you?
你确实想参加披萨派对，对吧？
Yes, but...
是的，但是……
Just go already.
赶紧去吧。
No one's coming.
没人来开门。
Try again.
再试一次。
Maybe there's no one home.
也许没人在家。
Of course there's someone home.
当然有人在。
There are two cars in the driveway and I can see lights on in the house.
车道上停着两辆车，而且我能看到屋里亮着灯。
Hello?
你好？
Anybody home?
有人在家吗？
We would like to know if you want to sponsor us in our school fundraiser.
我们想问您是否愿意赞助我们的学校筹款活动。
50% of the profits go towards the new school playground.
50%的利润将用于建设新的学校操场。
I don't know why anyone would want what's in this catalogue anyway.
反正我也不知道为什么会有人想要这本目录里的东西。
It's just a bunch of tacky Christmas ornaments, CDs of old people singing Christmas songs
就是一堆俗气的圣诞装饰品、老年人唱圣诞歌的CD、
and special crackers and cheeses and boxes of chocolates.
还有特别的饼干、奶酪和盒装巧克力。
You don't like chocolate?
你不喜欢巧克力吗？
Not this kind.
不是这种。
They've got weird names like ganache and praline.
它们有奇怪的名字，比如甘纳许和果仁糖。
Look, I just saw someone walking around inside.
看，我刚才看到有人在里面走动。
These people are being very rude.
这些人太没礼貌了。
Finally, someone's coming.
终于有人来了。
They don't look too happy.
他们看起来不太高兴。
Hi, sir.
您好，先生。
Would you like to sponsor us or make a donation to...
您愿意赞助我们或为……捐款吗？
What grade are you kids in?
你们是几年级的学生？
Grade 7.
七年级。
Then for goodness sake, don't you see this sign?
那看在上帝的份上，你们没看到这个牌子吗？
Can't you read?
你们不识字吗？
No soliciting?
禁止推销？
Alright so now we're back and we have four key phrases for you on Fluency Builder.
好了，现在我们回来了，在流利度训练中，我们为您准备了四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Okay, this first phrase is a pretty common one.
好的，第一个短语很常见。
We wanted to make sure that everyone was comfortable with the verb that goes with doorbell.
我们想确保每个人都熟悉与门铃搭配的动词。
So Marco, what do you do to a doorbell?
那么，马可，你对门铃做什么？
You ring the doorbell.
你按门铃。
So you don't touch it, you don't press it.
所以不是摸它，也不是压它。
You can press it, but you ring the doorbell.
你可以压它，但你是按门铃。
That's the verb.
这就是那个动词。
Okay, so for example, when I was little, my brother and I always used to fight about who
好的，举个例子，我小时候，我和哥哥总是争着
could ring the doorbell.
谁去按门铃。
Really?
真的吗？
Yes.
是的。
I loved ringing the doorbell and so did he.
我喜欢按门铃，他也喜欢。
Do you do the long ring or do you do the...
你是长按还是……
Ding, ding, ding, ding, ding, ding.
叮，叮，叮，叮，叮，叮。
You do it like that.
你就那样按。
The annoying ring.
那种烦人的按法。
Yeah, so to ring the doorbell.
是的，所以就是按门铃。
Alright, alright.
好了，好了。
And well, going back, when we were talking about no soliciting, you said that salespeople
嗯，回到之前，当我们谈到禁止推销时，你说销售人员
go door to door selling things.
会挨家挨户地推销东西。
So this is an interesting phrase and it's a fixed phrase, going door to door.
所以这是一个有趣的短语，而且是一个固定短语：挨家挨户。
Well, think about it.
嗯，想想看。
So a salesperson who wants to sell maybe some makeup goes to one house and no one wants
一个想卖化妆品的销售人员去了一家，没人想
to buy any makeup there.
在那里买化妆品。
So she goes to the next house.
所以她就去下一家。
So she's going from house to house.
所以她是从一家到另一家。
But we don't really say house to house because she's going to your door to offer the makeup.
但我们不常说“从一家到另一家”，因为她是在你家门口推销化妆品。
So we just say going door to door.
所以我们只说“挨家挨户”。
That means going to strangers' homes in order, one door after the next, to sell something.
意思是按顺序去陌生人的家，一家接一家地推销东西。
Very good.
很好。
You go door to door.
你挨家挨户地去。
So for example, someone can go door to door asking for some sugar.
比如，有人可以挨家挨户地要糖。
That's right.
没错。
Or we could say he is a door to door salesman.
或者我们可以说他是挨家挨户的推销员。
Door to door salesman.
挨家挨户的推销员。
Very good.
很好。
Alright.
好的。
And now we have an interesting question and it's a very good one because it's a question
现在我们有一个有趣的问题，而且这个问题非常好，因为它是一个
that comes up a lot.
经常被问到的问题。
When somebody asks you, if you're studying for example, what grade are you in?
当有人问你，比如你在上学，你上几年级？
Okay, what grade are you in?
好的，你上几年级？
So in the American system, for example, we have the very, very bottom, grade K, which
所以在美国的教育体系中，比如，最最底层是K年级，也就是
is kindergarten for maybe a five-year-old.
幼儿园，大概是五岁孩子上的。
And at the very top, we have high school, grade 12.
而最顶层是高中，12年级。
And so in between we have one, two, three, four, five, you know, and up.
中间则有一、二、三、四、五年级，等等，一直往上。
And so basically to find out what year in school a student is, you have to ask him or
所以基本上要了解一个学生上几年级，你得问他或
her, what grade are you in?
她，你上几年级？
Right.
对。
So then the person would say, I'm in sixth grade, I'm in eighth grade.
然后那个人会说，我上六年级，我上八年级。
But this is the way you ask this question for school as you said, a kid that's maybe
但这是你问学校年级的方式，就像你说的，针对可能
five years old all the way to 18 years old in high school.
五岁到18岁高中生的孩子。
What grade are you in?
你上几年级？
Now if you're in university and you want to ask your friend what year of university that
现在如果你在上大学，你想问你的朋友他上大几，
person's in, then you say, what year are you?
那么你会说，你上大几？
What year are you?
你上大几？
Yeah, you don't say grade.
是的，你不会说“年级”。
So basically grade refers to like what you said, Marco, those first 12 years of school.
所以基本上“年级”指的是像你说的，马可，那前12年的学校。
And so we call them, we thought, no, we don't call it grade 12.
我们叫它们，我们想，不，我们不叫它12年级。
So you could ask anybody under the age of 18, what grade are you in?
所以你可以问任何18岁以下的人，你上几年级？
But when you go to university or when you're talking about university students, it gets
但当你上大学或者谈论大学生时，情况就
a little bit different.
有点不同了。
So you can say, what year are you in or what year are you?
所以你可以说，你上大几？或者你上大几？
So if you're not sure about someone's age and you maybe think they're in college, you
所以如果你不确定某人的年龄，而且你可能觉得他们在上大学，你
can ask them, what year are you?
可以问他们，你上大几？
But generally anyone under 18, what grade are you in?
但一般来说，18岁以下的人，你上几年级？
Okay, good.
好的，不错。
All right.
好的。
And our last phrase, and this is kind of an expression, right?
还有我们最后一个短语，这算是一种表达方式，对吧？
Goodness sake, for goodness sake.
天哪，看在老天爷的份上。
Okay, so let's look at the context.
好的，让我们看看上下文。
The kids say, we're in grade seven.
孩子们说，我们上七年级。
And the person at the door says, then for goodness sake, don't you see this sign?
门口的人说，那看在老天爷的份上，你没看到这个牌子吗？
Right, for goodness sake.
对，看在老天爷的份上。
So this is an expression that's used to indicate maybe you're a little bit frustrated.
所以这是一种表达方式，用来表示你可能有点沮丧。
Yes.
是的。
Right.
对。
So it's like, come on, or my goodness, or for Pete's sake.
所以就像，拜托，或者我的天，或者看在彼得的份上。
So we have many ways of saying, all right, come on, I'm a little tired of this.
所以我们有很多种说法，比如，好吧，拜托，我有点烦这个了。
Right.
对。
You're irritating me.
你在惹恼我。
Right.
对。
So basically the person's saying, you are too old for this.
所以基本上那个人在说，你太老了，不适合这个。
You're too old for this.
你太老了，不适合这个。
You should read what it says on my door.
你应该读读我门上写的什么。
No soliciting.
禁止推销。
Right.
对。
And so the person's angry.
所以那个人很生气。
Right.
对。
Because these kids are trying to sell her something when clearly she has a sign that
因为这些孩子想卖给她东西，而她明明有个牌子写着
says no soliciting.
禁止推销。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
A lot of interesting phrases there.
那里有很多有趣的短语。
Why don't we go back, listen to our dialogue for the very last time, and we'll be back
我们为什么不回去，最后一次听我们的对话，然后我们会回来
to talk with you a little bit more.
再和你们多聊一会儿。
Okay, Mark, it's your turn to ring the doorbell.
好的，马克，轮到你去按门铃了。
I did it last time.
上次是我按的。
I hate going door to door and I hate asking for money.
我讨厌挨家挨户推销，也讨厌要钱。
But we need to raise enough money for the school fundraiser so that our class can win
但我们需要为学校筹款活动筹到足够的钱，这样我们班才能赢得
the pizza party.
披萨派对。
You do want to have a pizza party, don't you?
你确实想要一个披萨派对，对吧？
Yes, but...
是的，但是……
Just go already.
快去按吧。
No one's coming.
没人来开门。
Try again.
再试一次。
Maybe there's no one home.
也许没人在家。
Of course there's someone home.
当然有人在家。
There are two cars in the driveway and I can see lights on in the house.
车道上停着两辆车，而且我能看到房子里亮着灯。
Hello?
喂？
Anybody home?
有人在家吗？
We would like to know if you want to sponsor us in our school fundraiser.
我们想知道您是否愿意赞助我们的学校筹款活动。
50% of the profits go towards the new school playground.
50%的利润将用于新学校操场。
I don't know why anyone would want what's in this catalogue anyway.
我不知道为什么会有人想要这本目录里的东西。
It's just a bunch of tacky Christmas ornaments, CDs of old people singing Christmas songs,
只是一堆俗气的圣诞装饰品、老年人唱圣诞歌的CD、
and special crackers and cheeses and boxes of chocolates.
还有特别的饼干、奶酪和盒装巧克力。
You don't like chocolate?
你不喜欢巧克力吗？
Not this kind.
不是这种。
They've got weird names like ganache and praline.
它们有像甘纳许和果仁糖这样奇怪的名字。
Look, I just saw someone walking around inside.
看，我刚才看到有人在里面走动。
These people are being very rude.
这些人非常无礼。
Finally, someone's coming.
终于有人来了。
They don't look too happy.
他们看起来不太高兴。
Hi, sir.
你好，先生。
Would you like to sponsor us or make a donation to...
您愿意赞助我们或捐款给……
What grade are you kids in?
你们这些孩子上几年级了？
Grade 7.
七年级。
Then for goodness sake, don't you see this sign?
看在老天爷的份上，你们没看到这个牌子吗？
Can't you read?
你们不识字吗？
No soliciting?
禁止推销？
All right, so door-to-door salesman.
好吧，所以是上门推销员。
I think this used to be a very American thing.
我觉得这曾经是很美国化的事情。
I think back in the 50s, you would always see movies where this was actually a profession.
我想在50年代，你总能在电影里看到这其实是一种职业。
That's right.
没错。
People would go door-to-door selling hairbrushes or magazine subscriptions, pretty much everything.
人们会挨家挨户卖发刷或杂志订阅，几乎什么都卖。
Yeah, you still see it sometimes.
是啊，现在有时还能看到。
Some people sell insurance or there are a lot of religious door-to-door salespeople
有些人卖保险，或者有很多宗教上门推销员，
who want to sell religious books or magazines.
他们想卖宗教书籍或杂志。
But I think it was much more popular in the 1950s because people didn't really use their
但我认为这在50年代更流行，因为那时人们不太用
phones as much to sell things.
电话来卖东西。
It was cheaper to have someone drive his car to your neighborhood and then go to every
雇人开车到你的社区，然后挨家挨户
single house.
推销更便宜。
But yeah, it's a very interesting job.
不过，这确实是个很有趣的工作。
I think it'd be very lonely.
我觉得会很孤独。
And also, I think, well, now maybe that's been reduced a lot because now you have the
而且，我想，现在可能已经减少了很多，因为现在有了
internet.
互联网。
Oh yeah, well the internet means that the salespeople come to you without you having
哦对，互联网意味着推销员不用你
to get up.
起身就能找上门。
So basically, you're sitting at home in your pajamas and you can order a TV and some clothes.
所以基本上，你穿着睡衣坐在家里，就能订一台电视和一些衣服。
But it's very interesting because I remember you would have all these door-to-door salesmen.
但这很有趣，因为我记得以前有很多上门推销员。
For example, I had one visit me once who was selling me encyclopedias.
比如，有一次有个人来向我推销百科全书。
Really?
真的吗？
A big collection of like, I don't know, 37 books or more.
一大套，大概有37本书或更多。
It was a huge amount of books, encyclopedias.
那是很大一堆书，百科全书。
And I don't know if you see that anymore.
我不知道现在还能不能看到这个。
Not really, not in the States.
不太常见了，在美国不是。
I don't know if anyone buys physical, huge encyclopedias to have in their home.
我不知道还有没有人买实体的大部头百科全书放在家里。
No, only collectors perhaps.
没有，可能只有收藏家会买。
Maybe.
也许吧。
So it's a very interesting profession.
所以这是个很有趣的职业。
I don't know, in the United States, as you say, it's not very common anymore.
我不知道，在美国，就像你说的，现在已经不常见了。
Very little, maybe specific services.
非常少，可能只有特定的服务。
But this is interesting.
但这很有意思。
Maybe in your country, this is still a big thing.
也许在你的国家，这还是很普遍的事。
Yeah, let us know.
是啊，告诉我们吧。
In your country, are door-to-door salespeople still common?
在你的国家，上门推销员还常见吗？
Do you see them?
你见过他们吗？
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
All right, bye-bye.
好了，再见。
Bye-bye.
再见。